A Guide to the Papers of Kenneth W. Thompson 10/22/2002
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Kenneth W. Thompson 1952-1973
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12788
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The career of Kenneth Winfred Thompson spans the fields of education, scholarship in foreign relations, and philanthropy. He was born on August 29, 1921 in Des Moines, Iowa, the son of Thor Carlyle and Agnes (Rorbeck) Thompson. His family later moved to La Crosse, Wisconsin, where he attended public schools. He graduated from Augustana College (Rock Island, Illinois) in 1943, earning the degree of A.B. in History. Further academic training was interrupted by service during World War II; Dr. Thompson served in both theaters of combat, earning the rank of Lieutenant. During those years, he met Miss Lucille (Bette) Bergquist, whom he later married. Their family eventually included three sons.
Dr. Thompson's academic training was resumed at the University of Chicago, which awarded him the degree of Masters of Arts in 1948 and the Doctorate in Political Science and International Relations in 1950. He then served briefly on the staff of both the University of Chicago and Northwestern University before being appointed a consultant in international relations by the Rockefeller Foundation in October 1953.
Promotion within the Foundation followed quickly. Dr. Thompson was appointed Assistant Director for the Social Sciences on April 6, 1955, Associate Director two years later, and Director in 1960. Finally, he was elected Vice President of the Rockefeller Foundation on October 1, 1961, succeeding Charles W. Cole, who had been appointed U.S. ambassador to Chile.
Dr. Thompson is credited with having reorganized the major programs of the Rockefeller Foundation while serving as Vice President. At the same time, his activity as an author and on the platform was intense. During his years at the Rockefeller Foundation, he wrote or collaborated on eight books, published numerous articles, and was a much sought-for speaker on the subject of diplomacy and international affairs. He delivered the Riverside Memorial Lectures in 1958, the Lilly Endowment Lectures (Duke University) in 1959, the James Stokes Lectures (New York University) in 1962, and the Rockwell Lectures (Rice University) in 1965. All these lecture series were later published.
Dr. Thompson was heavily influenced by and closely associated with the late Reinhold Niebuhr, whose ideas on morality in social relations were echoed by Dr. Thompson and applied to the realm of international relations. At the same time, Dr. Thompson held himself to be a political "realist" and was often at odds with his theoretical opponents, such as Hans J. Morgenthau.
Dr. Thompson has been a member of the Council on Foreign Relations since 1955, and has been on the board of editors or a contributing editor to International Organization and Christianity Crisis since 1956. Although he relinquished the vice-presidency of the Rockefeller Foundation on January 1, 1974, he continues to serve the Foundation as a part-time consultant on international affairs. He is presently Director of Higher Education for International Development for the Council on Higher Education (since 1974) and Commonwealth Professor of Government and Foreign Affairs, University of Virginia (since 1975).
Scope and Content Information
The Kenneth W. Thompson Collection contains few signs of his day-to-day work for the Rockefeller Foundation. It provides a view into the workshop of a busy author and lecturer. The collection contains speeches, clippings, drafts of books, articles and reports, and correspondence relative to speaking engagements and problems of publication. Subjects covered include: international relations, diplomacy, higher education, foreign assistance, and Christian ethics.
Significant correspondents in this collection include John C. Bennet, Joseph E. Black, Raymond B. Fosdick, Stephen D. Kertesz, Arthur S. Link, A. William Loos, Hans J. Morgenthau, Reinhold Niebuhr, and Dean Rusk.
Single signed items by Hannah Arendt, Hubert H. Humphrey, Sir Harold Nicholson, and Arnold J. Toynbee also appear in this collection.
Organization
Following the original filing order, this collection has been arranged in six separate groups:
Group I: Speeches, Lectures, and Symposia (1955-1973) The material in this group consists of a file of speeches and lectures delivered by Dr. Thompson or symposia to which he contributed, and is arranged chronologically by the date of the event. Where a fair copy of his presentation exists, it takes precedence in the file, followed by any surviving drafts in order of composition. Programs of the event and supporting correspondence then follow, arranged chronologically. On many occasions, Dr. Thompson spoke extemporaneously or from notes which have not survived. In those cases, the file for that address consists of correspondence only. Many of these speeches and lectures were later reworked and published. In most cases, a brief note appears in the file for each address in question, giving the details of its appearance in print. Further material dealing with publication will be found in Group II and IV. A cross reference file-card index to this material is filed in Box 25.
Group II: Books (1955-1973) This group contains material related to books written, co-authored, or edited by Dr. Thompson, or to which he contributed. Following the original filing system, the material is arranged alphabetically by the title of each book. The file for each book begins with the most finished version of that book or portion of a book which has survived, whether reprint or typescript, followed by remaining drafts, in order of composition. In a few cases, where the text survives in clearly delineated stages (from draft to typescript to galley and page proof) that order has been followed. Correspondence related to publication then follows, with reviews and notes on distribution by Dr. Thompson concluding the file for each book. This group concludes with a set of published manuscripts also written by Dr. Thompson, together with rejected requests for articles and reviews. For further material, see Group VI.
Group III: Publications--General (1952-1972) The material in this group consists of reports, articles, and conference proceedings written or contributed to by Dr. Thompson, usually as part of a committee. Following the original filing system, the material is first arranged alphabetically by organization. It is then followed by a set of papers relating to Dr. Thompson's activity as a reader of manuscripts for publishers or authors, also arranged alphabetically. For further material, see Group VI.
Group IV: Articles (1952-1973) The material in this group consists of the texts and drafts of articles and reviews written by Dr. Thompson, together with correspondence pertaining to their publication. Following their original filing order, it is arranged alphabetically by journal title.
Group V: Christianity and Crisis (1955-1971) This group consists of material related to Dr. Thompson's activity as contributing editor of the journal Christianity and Crisis, a position he has held since 1956. This journal was founded by the late Reinhold Niebuhr and his colleagues; Mr. Wayne H. Cowan was the editor-in-chief during the years covered in this collection. This file opens with a single folder of correspondence relating to administrative matters, followed by material pertaining to the publication of Dr. Thompson's own articles in that journal. That material is arranged chronologically by date of publication. The file for each article opens with a copy of the article in its most finished form, usually an issue of the journal in which it appeared, followed by whatever drafts that have survived and supporting correspondence.
Group VI: Miscellany This group consists of oversize material, mainly galley-sheets of books written or edited by Dr. Thompson; photographs; and a file-card index (see Box 25) to the original files which was originally maintained by his secretaries.
Contents List
- Group I: Speeches, Lectures, and Symposia
  - Speeches 1955 Jan - 1962 Feb (Box 1)
    (7 folders)
  - Speeches 1962 May - 1965 Jun (Box 2)
    (6 folders)
  - Speeches 1965 Sep - 1967 Feb (Box 3)
  - Speeches 1967 Mar - 1968 Sep (Box 4)
  - Speeches 1968 Sep - 1970 Apr (Box 5)
  - Speeches 1970 May - 1972 Nov (Box 6)
  - Speeches 1972 Dec - 1973 Aug (Box 7)
  - Speeches 1973 Oct (Box 8)
    (2 folders)
- Group II: Books
  - A Man and His Mission: Paul M. Mitchell, 1973 (Box-folder 8:50)
    (reprint of KWT's contribution)
  - American Diplomacy and Emergent Patterns, 1962 (Box-folder 8:50)
    text of the James Stokes lectures
  - American...,1962 (Box-folder 8:51)
    test of the James Stokes Lectures; heading quotations; drafts of chapters
  - American...,1962 (Box-folder 8:52)
    drafts of chapters; notes on distribution
  - American...,1962 1960 Jun 27 - 1962 Dec 17 (Box-folder 9:53)
  - American...,1962 correspondence 1963 Jan 2 - 1969 Feb 6 (Box-folder 9:54)
    see Group VI for further material
  - Christian Ethics and the Dilemmas of Foreign Policy, 1959: correspondence 1957 Oct 25 - 1968 Nov 8 (Box-folder 9:55)
  - Christian..., 1959 (Box-folder 9:56)
    notes on distribution reviews; reviews
  - Christian Faith and the Liberal Arts, 1959: correspondence 1957 Jul 3 - 1960 Sep 7 (Box-folder 9:56)
  - Churches and States, ed. Kelman H. Silvert, 1967 (preface by KWT): text; correspondence 1967 Mar 6 - Oct 6 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Conflict and Cooperation among Nations, ed. by KWT with Ivo Duchacek, 1960: correspondence 1958 May 19 - 1966 Oct 4 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Contemporary International Politics, ed. Bruce C. Sanders and Alan Durbin, 1971 (article by KWT): correspondence 1971 Apr 9 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Contemporary Theory in Foreign Relations, ed. Stanley Hoffman, 1959 (two articles by KWT): correspondence 1971 Apr 9 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Contemporary Theory in Foreign Relations, ed. Stanley Hoffmann, 1959 (two articles by KTW): correspondence 1958 Sep 18-24 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Cultural Affairs and Foreign Relations, ed Paul J. Braisted, 1968 (article by KWT): text; correspondence 1962 Jul 3 - 1968 Aug 21 (Box-folder 9:57)
  - Democracies and International Relations, ed. Whitaker, 1962 (article by KWT): text; correspondence 1961 Nov 29 - Dec 1 (Box-folder 9:58)
  - Expectant Peoples, ed. Kalman H. Silvert, 1963 (preface by KWT): text; correspondence 1962 Aug 14 - 1964 Sep 8 (Box-folder 9:58)
  - Foreign Assistance: A View from the Private Sector, 1972: preliminary drafts (Box-folder 9:58)
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:59)
    preliminary drafts
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:60)
    drafts for preface and chapters I-II
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:61)
    drafts for chapters III-IV
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:62)
    drafts for chapter V
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:63)
    drafts for chapter VI
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 10:64)
    drafts for chapter VII and index
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 11:65)
    corrected typescript
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 11:66)
    printer's copy
  - Foreign Assistance... (Box-folder 11:67)
    (see group VI for galley proofs); notes on distribution and reviews
  - Foreign Assistance... 1971 Oct 21 - 1972 Oct 18 (Box-folder 11:68)
    correspondence
  - Foreign Assistance... 1972 Oct 21 - 1974 Feb 18 (Box-folder 11:69)
  - Foreign Policies in a World of Change, ed. KWT with Joseph E. Black, 1963: text of KWT contribution (Box-folder 11:70)
  - Foreign Policies..., 1963: correspondence with Joseph E. Black 1960 Jul 13 - 1961 Dec 26 (Box-folder 12:71)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with Joseph E. Black 1961 Dec 29 - 1963 May 29 (Box-folder 12:72)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with contributors (Box-folder 12:73)
    arranged by country (Argentina-China)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with contributors (Box-folder 12:74)
    (Denmark-East Africa)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with contributors (Box-folder 12:75)
    (Egypt-Japan)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with contributors (Box-folder 12:76)
    (Mexico-Switzerland)
  - Foreign Policies...: correspondence with contributors (Box-folder 12:77)
    (Tunisia-Yugoslavia); correspondence with publishers; misc. correspondence
  - Foreign Policies in World Politics, ed. Ray C. Macrides, 1958 (KWT article): correspondence 1957 Aug 20 - 1967 Mar 6 (Box-folder 13:78)
  - Foreign Policy...: correspondence 1970 Mar 16 - 1972 Jun 14 (Box-folder 13:79)
  - Higher Education in a World of Conflict, ed. George S. Parthemos, 1962 (KWT article): correspondence 1962 Mar 29 - Apr 2 (Box-folder 13:79)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1968 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1962 Mar 29 - Apr 2 (Box-folder 13:79)
  - Isolation and Security, ed. Alexander DeConte, 1957 (KWT article): correspondence 1957 Mar 28 - Dec 23 (Box-folder 13:79)
  - Last Chance in Europe, by Charles O. Lerche, Jr. (edited with a forward by KWT), 1967: text of foreword; copy of Lerche's typescript (Box-folder 13:80)
  - Last Chance...: Lerche's typescript; correspondence 1966 Sep 28 - 1967 Apr 17 (Box-folder 13:81)
  - Die Lehre von den internationalen Beziehungen, ed. E.O. Czempiel, 1963 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1965 Jul 12 - 1969 May 1 (Box-folder 13:82)
  - Liber Amicorum in Honor of Professor Alf Ross, 1969(KWT article): text; correspondence 1968 Jul 10 - 1970 Aug 20 (Box-folder 13:82)
  - Man and Modern Society, ed. KWT with Karl de Schweinitz, 1953: correspondence 1955 Jul 10 - 1970 Jul 21 (Box-folder 13:82)
  - The Moral Issue in Statecraft, 1966: text (Box-folder 13:82)
  - The Moral Issue...: text (Box-folder 13:82)
  - The Moral Issue...: correspondence 1965 Mar 16 - 1967 Jul 18 (Box-folder 13:84)
  - The Moral Issue...: correspondence 1967 Jul 31 - 1973 Jan 29 (Box-folder 14:85)
  - Nuclear Weapons and the Conflict of Conscience, ed. John C. Bennett, 1962 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1960 Jul 15 - 1963 Feb 4 (Box-folder 14:85)
  - Political Realism and the Crisis of World Politics, 1966: text (Box-folder 14:86)
  - Political Realism...: correspondence (1960 Mar 8 - 1973 Jan 29) (Box-folder 14:87)
  - Political Realism...: reviews (Box-folder 14:88)
  - Principles and Problems of International Politics, ed. by KWT with Hans J. Morgenthau, 1957: correspondence 1958 Oct 17 - 1966 Jul 6 (Box-folder 14:88)
  - Readings from Left to Right, ed. Victor E. Amend and Leo T. Hendrik, 1970 (KWT article): correspondence 1970 Feb 3 (Box-folder 14:88)
  - Reinhold Niebuhr, ed. Charles W. Kigley and Robert W. Bretall, 1956 (KWT article): text; drafts; correspondence 1963 Nov 3 - 1965 Jun 16 (Box-folder 14:88)
  - Responsible Government in a Revolutionary Age, ed. Z.K. Matthews, 1965 (KWT article): text; drafts; correspondence 1963 Nov 3 - 1965 Jun 16 (Box-folder 14:88)
  - Science and the University, ed. Boyd R. Keenan, 1966 (KWT article): text (Box-folder 14:89)
  - Science...: correspondence 1964 Oct 2 - 1966 Sep 15 (Box-folder 14:90)
  - Science et Conscience de la Societe, ed. Jean-Claude Casanova, 1971 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1969 Feb 13 - 1972 Aug 10 (Box-folder 15:91)
  - Studies in Politics, ed. M.S. Rajan, 1971 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1966 Jul 12 - 1972 Sep 14 (Box-folder 15:92)
  - The Moral Dilemma of Nuclear Weapons, ed. William Clancey, 1961 (KWT article): text (Box-folder 15:92)
  - The Search for World Order, ed. Albert Lepawsky et al, 1971 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1968 Feb 8 - 1972 Jun 12 (Box-folder 15:93)
  - The Task of Universities in a Changing World, ed. Stephen Z. Kertesz, 1971 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1968 Nov 29 - 1973 Jun 20 (Box-folder 15:94)
  - Theology and the Church in Times of Change, ed. Edward L. Long, Jr., and Robert T. Handy, 1970 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1967 Sep 4 - 1969 Apr 16 (Box-folder 15:95)
  - Theology and Church...: correspondence 1969 Apr 28 - 1970 Jun 4 (Box-folder 15:96)
  - Theory of International Relations, ed. Abdul A. Said, 1968 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1966 Dec 10 - 1969 May (Box-folder 15:96)
  - Toynbee and World History, ed. Ashley Montague, 1955: correspondence 1955 Aug 19-24 (Box-folder 16:97)
  - US Policy in the Far East, by KWT et. al., 1968: text, correspondence 1967 Jun 28 - 1968 Nov 8 (Box-folder 16:97)
  - What the Christian Hopes for in Society, ed. Wayne H. Cowan, 1957 (KWT article): correspondence 1957 Sep 19 - Oct 4 (Box-folder 16:97)
  - Witness to a Generation, ed. Wayne H. Cowan, 1966 (KWT article): correspondence 1967 Jan 23 - 26 (Box-folder 16:97)
  - A World in Change, ed. Ross N. Serkes, 1967 (KWT article): text; correspondence 1966 Mar 23 - 1968 Dec 10 (Box-folder 16:97)
  - Yearbook of World Affairs, 1959 (KWT article): text (Box-folder 16:97)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts (Box-folder 16:98)
  - Christian Century, 1959: review (Box-folder 16:98)
  - "The Eisenhower Doctrine," c. 1957 (Box-folder 16:98)
  - Institute for Religious and Social Studies: correspondence 1957 Jan 22 - Jul 12 (Box-folder 16:98)
  - New Leader:"Diplomacy and Psychology" 1960 Nov 11 - 1961 Apr 4 (Box-folder 16:98)
  - "Russian and Soviet Foreign Policy," c. 1965 (Box-folder 16:98)
  - The Yale Review: correspondence 1958 Jan 30 - Sep 10 (Box-folder 16:99)
  - "A New Strategy for International Development," 1969 (fall) (Box-folder 16:99)
  - "American Foreign Policy: The Post War Era," 1965 Jan (Box-folder 16:99)
  - Rejected Requests for Articles and Reviews 1957 Feb 20 - 1961 Oct 10 (Box-folder 16:99)
- Group III: Publications -- General
  - Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Scientists 1970 Oct (Box-folder 16:101)
  - American Assembly 1967 Apr 27 - 30 (Box-folder 16:101)
  - Association of Colleges and Universities for International-Intercultural Studies 1973 Oct (Box-folder 16:101)
  - Church Peace Union 1957 Jan 11 (Box-folder 16:101)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Teaching (1968): report; draft 1 (Box-folder 16:102)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Teaching (1968): draft 2 (Box-folder 16:103)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Teaching (1968): draft 3 (Box-folder 16:104)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Teaching (1968): drafts of chapters; correspondence (Box-folder 16:105)
  - Conference on Foreign Relations 1959 May 7 - 8 (Box-folder 16:106)
  - Council on Religion and International Affairs (1961) (Box-folder 16:106)
  - Cultural Relations for the Future: see Group VI 1972 Jul 17 - 23 (Box-folder 16:107)
  - Headline Series 1959 Nov - Dec (Box-folder 17:108)
  - International Council for Educational Development: text of report 1972 Nov (Box-folder 17:108)
  - International Council...correspondence; notes on distribution (Box-folder 17:109)
  - Macalaster College 1965 Apr 30 (Box-folder 17:110)
  - Michigan State University - Seminar on Thailand 1969 Jun 29 - Jul 1 (Box-folder 17:110)
  - Minnesota Higher Education Coordinating Committee 1970 Dec (Box-folder 17:110)
  - National Council of Churches 1958 Nov 18 - 1960 Nov (Box-folder 18:111)
  - "National Identity and Cultural Relations" 1972 Apr 3 (Box-folder 18:111)
  - New York University - Institute for Annual Review of UN Affairs 1961, 1962, 1963 (Box-folder 18:111)
  - Social Science Research Council 1952 summer (Box-folder 18:112)
  - United Church of Christ 1963 Dec 20 (Box-folder 18:113)
  - United Lutheran Church 1969 Apr 27 (Box-folder 18:113)
  - United Nations Association 1969 Apr 27 (Box-folder 18:113)
  - West Virginia Wesleyan College 1970 May 24 (Box-folder 18:113)
  - World Council of Churches 1969 Oct 20 - 23 (Box-folder 18:114)
  - Miscellaneous Manuscript Readings:
    - American Journal of Sociology 1966 Oct 27 - Nov 7 (Box-folder 18:114)
    - California State College at Fullerton 1966 Aug 9 - 30 (Box-folder 18:114)
    - Cambridge University Press 1964 Sep 18 - Oct 8 (Box-folder 18:114)
    - Church Peace Union 1958 Oct 7 - 1959 May 4 (Box-folder 18:114)
    - Coplin, William David, "An Assessment of Realism: Kennan and Thompson" 1961 Jan 2 - 1963 Jan 31 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - Corrin, B.S. 1957 Feb 10 - 1959 Jun 29 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - Hechscher, August, "The Public Happiness" 1962 Aug 1 - Sep 18 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - Journal of Politics 1964 Apr 22 - 1967 Nov 17 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - Landau, Martin 1959 Jun 25 - 30 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - Moseman, Albert H. 1964 Nov 6 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - North Central Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1956 Feb 10 - 1959 Dec 22 (Box-folder 18:115)
    - North Central... (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Olson, William C. 1972 Aug 31 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Pachter, N.M. 1957 May 26 - Jun 6 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Padover, Saul K. 1959 Jun 15 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Pearce, Anthony J. 1962 Apr 10 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Perkins, Anthony J. 1963 Oct 11 - 1964 Jan 7 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Prentice-Hall, Inc. 1962 Jan 11 - 1968 Nov 15 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Princeton University Press 1967 Sep 15 - Oct 23 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Random House, Inc. 1962 Jun 11 - 1968 Nov 15 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Review of Politics 1968 Feb 14 - Apr 9 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Rothschild, Richard C., "Bridge to Religion in an Age of Science" 1962 Jun 11 - Oct 18 (Box-folder 18:116)
    - Rudzinski, Alexander W.: manuscript on U.N. General Assembly Procedure 1959 (Box-folder 18:117)
    - Rudzinski, Alexander W. (Box-folder 19:118)
    - Rudzinski, Alexander W. (Box-folder 19:119)
    - Scribner's 1964 Nov 6 - 1965 Nov 22 (Box-folder 19:119)
    - Sharp, Samuel L., "Political Realism and Christian Realism" 1963 Nov 8 (Box-folder 19:119)
    - World Council of Churches 1960 Apr 22 - May 20 (Box-folder 19:119)
- Group IV: Articles
  - Americana--Japanese Issue 1956 May (Box-folder 19:120)
  - American Political Science Review--2 articles 1953 Sep - 1955 Sep (Box-folder 19:120)
  - American Political Science Review--4 articles 1958 Jun - 1971 Dec (Box-folder 19:121)
  - Annals of the Academy of Political and Social Scientists--5 articles 1960 Sep - 1966 Jul (Box-folder 19:121)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Reprint Series (1962) (Box-folder 19:122)
  - The Center Magazine-- 2 articles 1972 Sep - 1973 Dec (Box-folder 19:122)
  - The Christian Advocate 1960 Jun (Box-folder 19:122)
  - The Christian Century 1958 Jan (Box-folder 19:123)
  - Commonweal--3 articles 1958 Apr 4 - 1961 Jun 2 (Box-folder 19:123)
  - Cross Currents 1960 summer (Box-folder 19:123)
  - Dialog-- 3 articles 1963 autumn - 1971 autumn (Box-folder 19:124)
  - Encyclopedia Americana--entry on Arnold J. Toynbee 1971 (Box-folder 19:124)
  - Ethics 1955 Jul (Box-folder 19:124)
  - Foro Internacional 1960 Jul - Sep (Box-folder 20:125)
  - Foundation News 1970 Sep - Oct (Box-folder 20:125)
  - Friends Journal 1973 Mar 15 (Box-folder 20:125)
  - The Intercollegian 1956 May (Box-folder 20:125)
  - International Journal 1958 autumn (Box-folder 20:125)
  - International Journal of Religious Education 1967 Feb (Box-folder 20:125)
  - International Organization 1968 Jun (Box-folder 20:126)
  - International Studies Quarterly 1965 summer (Box-folder 20:126)
  - Journal of Conflict Resolution--2 articles 1958 Jun - 1971 Dec (Box-folder 20:127)
  - Journal of Higher Education 1966 May (Box-folder 20:127)
  - Journal of International Affairs 1967 summer (Box-folder 20:127)
  - Journal of Politics 1958 Aug (Box-folder 20:128)
  - Journal of Presbyterian History 1972 spring (Box-folder 20:128)
  - Lutheran World 1968 Jun (Box-folder 20:128)
  - National War College Reprint 1963 (Box-folder 20:129)
  - National Law Forum 1961 (Box-folder 20:129)